救雪莉.
Save Shelly.
为什么, 这世上谁会
放走布里格斯少校, 里欧?
Why, who in the world
let Major Briggs loose, Leo?
除了你, 还有谁?
lt couldn't have been you, could it?
不, 不. 没有刑罚了, 里欧.
No, no. No punishment, Leo.
现在对我们做出任何伤害
都为时已晚了.
lt's too late for that
to do us any harm.
我和你玩个新游戏吧.
And l have a new game for you.
看, 这就是我们赞助给
双峰小姐节日自助餐的.
Well, here's our contribution
to the Miss Twin Peaks gala buffet.
而我满怀希望见到你们中的
一个能成为那里的赢家.
And l fully expect to see one of you
up there in the winner's circle.
- 做梦呢, 诺玛.
- 别那么肯定.
- Dream on, Norma.
- Don't be so sure.
这可是我们一年中
最重要的日子.
This is the biggest day of the year
for us.
我们必须得有人去
搞出点名堂来
And we have to have somebody
up there
有人就配拿这个奖.
who really deserves this title.
特别是今年.
Especially this year.
你是指劳拉·帕尔默?
You mean Laura Palmer?
是个能冲冲喜的好日子.
lt would be a good day for healing.
我想不只需要1天呢.
l think we need more than a day.
那, 诺玛, 他们今晚会
颁你荣誉奖吗?
So, Norma, are they gonna
honor you tonight
庆祝你当选双峰小姐
20周年纪念日
on your 20th anniversary
of winning Miss Twin Peaks?
别提我了.
Don't remind me.
真的,
如果你今天还去参选的话, 你会赢的.
Come on,
if you entered today, you'd win.
瞧瞧你们,
是想来影响评委的吧.
Look at you,
you're already working on the judge.
那好, 既然你提到这...
Well, since you mentioned it...
你打算要投谁一票?
Who are you gonna vote for?
可能你要把选票分成两半了.
Maybe you could split your vote.
- 嗨, 爸爸.
- 欧蕊.
- Hi, Daddy.
- Audrey.
这是我今天见过
最有才气的一张脸.
The most intelligent face
that l've seen all day.
你让其余的人都相形见绌
让我们看起来都像灵长类了.
You make the rest of us
look like primates.
都拿着什么书啊?
What's with all the books?
是, 《古兰经》,
Yes, the Koran,
福音《博伽梵歌》, 《太教法典》,
the Bhagavad-Gita, the Talmud,
《圣经》, 《旧约》和《新约》,
the Bible, Old and New Testaments,
《道德经》.
the Tao Te Ching.
欧蕊, 我手中拿着的
这些圣书
Audrey, l hold in my hands
those holy books
组成了
人性本善
which constitute
the fundamental framework
这个哲学体系的
基本架构.
of humanity's
philosophy of good.
在这里面
有我所寻求的答案.
Somewhere in here
are the answers that l seek.
我打算把他们从头到尾
透彻地读遍, 直到我找出...
And l intend to read them
from cover to cover, until l find...
听我在这儿唠唠叨叨的.
Listen to me prattling on.
是杰克的事吧?
lt's Jack, isn't it?
才过了一天而已.
lt's only been a day.
我希望这一周
不要太痛苦就好.
l hope it doesn't hurt this much
in a week.
小蜜糖, 我能给你
一个永恒的智慧吗?
Honey, may l give you
a piece of ageless wisdom
是节选自这些册子的
culled from these volumes?
时间抚平一切伤口.
Time heals all wounds.
我知道那感觉的滋味.
l know how it feels.
相信我.
Believe me.
我们几乎没有时间
去彼此了解.
We barely had time
to know each other.
但你有过的时光
都是精华.
But the time that you had
was highly concentrated.
精华中的
精华.
lt's the concentrate
they make concentrate from.
恐怕我永远不会再见到他了.
l'm afraid l'll never see him again.
杰克是个说话算话的人.
Jack is a man of his word.
如果他说了回来,
那他就会回来.
And if he said that he'd be back,
then he will be back.
我向你保证.
l promise you.
爸爸, 你无法向我保证的,
但还是谢谢你的祝愿
Daddy, you can't promise me,
but thanks for wanting to.
我来这儿，其实是向你
讲一下西雅图一行的事.
l actually came here
to update you on my trip to Seattle.
对. 开始吧.
Right. Update away.
好的.
Okay.
帕卡家族正通过动用双峰镇的
储备基金和贷款
The Packards are using
Twin Peaks Savings and Loan
将现金注入
格斯伍计划.
to funnel cash
to the Ghostwood project.
但银行保持的
非常低调.
But the bank is keeping
a very low profile.
似乎他们不想
有任何不利影响.
lt seems they don't want
any bad publicity.
哦, 是吗?
Oh, they don't?
好啊, 负面影响
正是他们将会得到的.
Well, bad publicity
is exactly what they're gonna get.
欧蕊, 去参加双峰小姐
的选美盛会
Audrey, have you given
any more thought
你考虑的怎么样了?
to the Miss Twin Peaks Pageant?
爸爸...
Daddy...
我打心底里,
From the bottom of my heart,
可不想做什么
镇中之花.
l don't wanna be
the town bathing beauty.
我理解.
l understand.
但双峰小姐是
地方的终极论坛.
But Miss Twin Peaks
is the ultimate local forum.
欧蕊.
Audrey.
它真的会很鼓舞人心
lt would truly be inspirational
一个有政治
触觉的赢家
to have a winner
with a political sensibility
将远远胜过
那些只有化妆策略
that extends
beyond makeup strategies
和秘方樱桃馅饼的参选者, 哼?
and recipes for cherry pie, huh?
现在, 如你所知,
Now, as you know,
全镇集结，每个参赛者
都会向全镇的人发表演讲.
each contestant gives a speech
to the assembled town.
今年的主题，是我们
切身相关的环境问题.
This year's theme concerns
our immediate environment.
恰恰就是我们要坚定保护的东西.
And what we must do to preserve it.
我知道还有别的方法可以做到的,
爸爸.
l know there's another way to do this,
Daddy.
欧蕊, 发表演讲吧.
Audrey, make the speech.
协助制止格斯伍.
Help stop Ghostwood.
让我们的日子过的更美好.
And take us to a better day.
他回去休息了吗?
Has he taken his eyes off it yet?
今天没有.
Not today.
你来问之前,
And before you ask,
我还派人出去林子里
彻底搜索布里格斯少校.
we still got people out
combing the woods for Major Briggs.
哈里, 鉴于我们和蓝皮书项目
之间都有联系,
Harry, considering our mutual
connection to Project Blue Book,
我相信，云顿·厄尔
已经盯上少校了.
l believe that Windom Earle
has targeted the major.
- 为了什么?
- 有意思.
- What for?
- lnteresting.
我不知道.
l don't know.
但你容许的话,
我敢响亮的说.
But with your permission,
l'd like to speak out loud.
云顿·厄尔早在1965年
就已经在探索进入
Windom Earle has been
seeking access to the Black Lodge
守夜门的途径了.
as far back as 1 965.
那个象棋游戏牵涉到的线索
This chess game may involve
可能比我们
刚开始想像的还要多.
more pieces
than we've begun to imagine.
继而,
值得要去考虑一下
Then of course,
there's the mysterious circumstances
有些围绕乔西的死
出现的神秘事件.
surrounding Josie's death
to consider.
是什么事件?
要怎么去考虑?
What about them?
Consider them how?
她死的时候-- 我很抱歉
之前没有提到这个, 哈里,
When she died-- l'm sorry
l didn't mention this before, Harry,
但我不得不顾及到
你的精神状态.
but l had to take into account
your mental state.
到底是什么?
What is it?
她当时恐惧的颤抖着.
She was trembling with fear.
我会尽可能的说
像一头发抖的动物.
l would go as far as to say
quaking like an animal.
我可以大胆猜测说
是那恐惧杀死了她.
l might venture a guess to say
that it was the fear that killed her.
她死的那一刻...
At the moment of her death...
...我看见了鲍勃.
...l saw Bob.
彷彿他穿行并
滑进时间的缝隙.
As if he had slipped in
through some crevice in time.
再反覆思量, 我相信
他的出现
Upon reflection, l believe
there's a connection
和乔西的恐惧之间
是有联系的.
between his appearance
and Josie's fear.
就像他被它吸引了.
As if he was attracted to it.
并以此为食.
Feeding off it somehow.
你觉得鲍勃和守夜门
之间有关系?
You see a connection
between Bob and the Black Lodge?
哈里,
我觉得他就来自那里.
Harry,
l think it's where he comes from.
我想这守夜门就是
你过去提起过的
l think that the Black Lodge
is what you have referred to in the past
那股 "树林里的邪恶."
as ''the evil in these woods.''
如果云顿·厄尔正在
寻求进入那里,
lf Windom Earle is seeking access
to that,
那我们势必要以我们的方式
比他先进入.
it is imperative that we find our way in
before he does.
那里是一个巨大的能量源,
哈里.
There's a source of great power there,
Harry.
远远超出了我们
所能理解的.
Far beyond our ability
to comprehend.
终于找到了!
Eureka!
戴尔, 我真该吻吻
你的小尖头.
Dale, l could kiss
your pointy little head.
是恐惧.
lt's fear.
是恐惧, 里欧. 那就是关键.
lt's fear, Leo. That's the key.
我最喜爱的情绪状态.
My favorite emotional state.
而这期间,
原来它就一直近在我眼前.
And all this time,
it's been staring me right in the kisser.
里欧, 这真叫人惊讶, 绝配.
Leo, it's marvelous, a perfect fit.
这些盘旋在
我们噩梦边缘的黑夜生物
These night creatures that hover
on the edge of our nightmares
每当我们放射出恐惧
它们就会被吸引过来.
are drawn to us
when we radiate fear.
因为那就是它们的黄油面包.
lt's their bread and butter.
一个完美的共生.
A perfect symbiosis.
噢, 大自然,
设计和外观都完美无瑕.
Oh, nature,
perfect in design and aspects.
你不会失望的!
You do not disappoint!
里欧, 鼓足干劲.
Leo, look lively.
胜利在望了.
Victory is at hand.
我们知道哪里是入口了.
我们知道闸门几时会出现了.
We know where the entrance is.
We know when the lock appears.
现在钥匙在我们手中了.
Now we hold the key in our hands.
原谅我要仓促离开了,
亲爱的人儿.
Forgive my hasty departure,
dear one.
时候已经到了，把我
心爱的皇后们聚集起来了
The time has come
to gather my beloved queen
登上我们的
黑暗蜜月之旅吧.
and embark
upon our dark honeymoon.
自从我刺穿了凯若琳的大动脉后
我一直没有这么兴奋过了.
l haven't been this excited
since l punctured Caroline's aorta.
里欧, 我们一定要分享一下
最后的伤感情调.
Leo, we must share
a final sentiment.
我们在葱郁凉亭
一起相处的这段时光,
During our time together
in this verdant bower,
我必须承认, 我对你
产生了一种溺爱.
l must confess, l've developed
something of a fondness for you.
传声筒, 伴侣,
Sounding board, companion,
永远服从和忠诚.
ever obedient and faithful.
总的来说成绩是A，里欧.
An overall A for effort, Leo.
但我还是有点恼火
你放走了布里格斯少校.
But l'm still a trifle miffed
at your release of Major Briggs.
不过, 你将会有足够的时间
在这事上好好反省, 是不?
But then, you'll have plenty of time
to reflect upon that, won't you?
再见了, 里欧.
Goodbye, Leo.
祝你好运.
And good luck.
1，2, 和3，4步先前.
One and two and three, step four.
再来1，2,--
让情绪带动着你.
And one and two--
Let the mood carry you.
不要害怕你的弱点.
再多漏点腿.
Don't be afraid of your vulnerability.
Show me more leg.
这到底是什么
舞蹈啊, 品寇先生?
What kind of a dance
is this supposed to be, Mr. Pinkle?
这是大自然之舞, 我的朋友.
lt's a dance of nature, my friend.
这一种庆祝的仪式.
好了, 女生们.
lt's a celebration.
All right, girls.
现在, 转身
向前弯腰
Now, turn around
and bend forward
像小树苗一样.
一颗在风中的小树苗.
like a sapling.
A sapling in the wind.
那样就对了. 再弯一点, 然后停住.
That's it. A little bit more, and hold it.
我们全都弯成这个样子
到底为了庆祝什么啊?
What exactly are we celebrating
with us all bending over like this?
永远不要质疑你们的
舞蹈指导所编排的视觉效果!
Don't ever question the vision
of your choreographer!
你们不过是我玫瑰花上的其中一瓣.
You are but a petal on my rose.
现在, 麻烦大家.
从一开始数.
Now, please, people.
On the count of one.
1，2，3，4.
One and two and three and four.
再来1，2
And one and two
- 3，4...
- 我最爱歌舞大合唱了.
- and three and four...
- l love a chorus line.
我们这里能否稍微
抓紧一点.
lf we could just focus here
for a second.
我还得回餐厅去.
l've gotta get back to the diner.
好了, 我们认为双峰小姐
最典型的品质应该是什么?
Now, what qualities do we think
best exemplify Miss Twin Peaks?
美丽和能量.
Beauty and power.
它们是我所喜欢的.
That's the way l like them.
自信, 上帝快帮帮我们吧,
和善于交际
Poise and, God help us,
a sophistication
还要有教养.
and breeding.
嗯, 我觉得还有一个主要的因素
就是独创精神和见解.
Well, l think a major factor
should be originality.
那, 不是应该归为才艺类吗?
Well, wouldn't that fall under talent?
有独创精神好啊.
lt's always nice when it does.
就我个人而言,
体面的外表永远是大事.
Personally,
l've always been big on style.
我想这
够我忙活了,
l think this is enough
for me to work with,
那我先回去
准备好这些评分表,
so l'm gonna go back
and work up the scoresheets,
我们今晚见吧.
and l'll see you tonight.
- 好极了.
- 再见.
- Terrific.
- Bye.
再来3，4.
And three and four.
好了, 大伙休息一下.
Okay, that's a break, team.
嗨, 基巴. 我们休息了.
Hi, Dick. We're on break.
嗨, 拉娜.
Hi, Lana.
你介意帮我到储物室
找点东西吗?
Would you mind helping me
find something in the storage room?
储物室?
Storage room?
我们一个非常重要的
道具不见了.
We're missing
a very important prop.
来吧.
Come on.
我看不清楚.
l'm having trouble.
那, 打开它不就看到了.
Well, just flick it.
那么, 你到底
需要找什么?
Now, what exactly
did you need to find?
- 拉娜?
- 噢, 是我熄了么?
- Lana?
- Oh, did l do that?
你要找什么?
What are you looking for?
好了, 这样, 我不知道
那个东西的专业名称是什么, 但...
Well, now, l don't know
the exact technical name for it, but...
那有什么东西--?
这儿有什么东西看起来像的?
Does anything--?
Does anything in here look like it?
噢, 我想这个就是了.
Oh, l think this might be it.
?, 天啊, 我想你找到它了.
Oh, by George, l think you've got it.
黛安, 现在是下午1:17.
我刚刚结束了
Diane, it's 1 :1 7 p.m.
l have just concluded
今天代替睡眠的
第二次冥想.
my second meditation of the day
in lieu of sleep.
我感觉精神完全恢复过来了
让我再次感悟到
And l feel completely refreshed
and struck again by the realization
我们所有人
都只不过是生活在
that all of us on this great big
planet Earth
这个伟大行星地球上
潜在的一粒小分子.
live at only a fraction
of our potential.
我们日以继夜为那幅
洞穴岩石雕刻忙碌.
We are working round the clock
on the cave petroglyph.
我肯定答案就在
这幅神秘的版画里.
l am certain that the answers lie
in this mysterious etching.
我也确信
云顿·厄尔
l am also convinced
that Windom Earle
正在搜寻
和我们一样的东西
is searching for exactly
the same thing as we are
只不过他的理由却截然相反.
for diametrically opposite reasons.
关于那块不洁之地所含能量的假设
如果我是正确的,
lf l'm correct in my assumptions
about the power of this unholy place,
让他捷足先登的话，就只能等上帝打救了.
God help us if he gets there first.
黛安, 在这个特别的时刻,
Diane, at this particular juncture,
我想特别提一下
安妮·伯本.
l would like to make specific mention
of Annie Blackburn.
她完全是一个
原始人类.
She is a completely original
human being.
她的回答,
就像孩子般单纯.
Her responses,
as pure as those of a child.
我必须诚实, 除了凯若琳
我还未对一个女人有过这样的感觉.
l must be honest, l haven't felt this way
about a woman since Caroline.
遇见安妮之后
才让我意识到
lt has taken meeting Annie
for me to realize
自从凯若琳死后
我的生活是多么灰暗.
how gray my life has been
since Caroline's death.
多么寒冷和孤独.
How cold and solitary.
虽然偶尔觉得,
Although occasionally,
独居
也不错.
there is something to be said
for solitude.
安妮·伯本,
你来得太是时候了.
Annie Blackburn,
you have almost perfect timing.
我们的舞指
可不会这么说.
That's not
what our choreographer says.
我能为你做点什么吗?
What can l do for you?
嗯, 6小时后
我就要发表演讲了.
Well, l need to give a speech
in six hours.
我连一个字都还没写,
l haven't written a word,
而且我也不知道
我要讲什么.
and l don't have any idea
what l wanna say.
我紧张的
掌心直冒汗,
l'm in a complete
sweaty-palmed panic,
我需要找个人谈谈,
就是你.
and l need to talk to someone,
namely you.
你的主题是什么?
What's your topic?
你能做什么
去拯救我们本地的森林.
What you can do
to save our local forests.
我只是不想站在那里
像个神经错乱的芭比娃娃,
l just don't wanna stand up there
like some deranged Barbie doll,
讲些什么,像
"确保你的营火熄灭了,
saying things like,
''Make sure your campfires are out,
有点像我的脑袋."之类的傻话
kind of like my brain.''
- 你对向公众演讲有恐惧.
- 是的.
- You're terrified of public speaking.
- Yes.
那行, 这样...
All right, well...
...我们的森林需要拯救
因为我们对待它们的方式.
...our forests need saving because
of the way people regard them.
是破坏.
Expendable.
如果格斯伍的发展
是以成千上万性命为代价的话,
lf the Ghostwood development
cost thousands of lives,
你觉得它还有
前进的机会吗?
do you think it would have
a chance of going forward?
虽然, 树木和人
不一样.
Well, trees aren't the same
as people.
但它们是有生命的.
But they are alive.
你的森林是美丽
而平和的.
Your forest is beautiful
and peaceful.
部分已经遭到损坏了.
Part of it's been damaged.
我尝试再植,
但都没法扎根了.
l've tried to replant,
but nothing's taken root.
每个森林都自己的影子.
Every forest has its shadow.
我能从你的脸上
看到我半生的历史,
l can see half my life's history
in your face,
而我不肯定那是否我想要的.
and l'm not sure that l want to.
我不想再聊
树的事了.
l don't wanna talk about trees
anymore.
我只知道,
我要和你做爱.
All l know is,
l wanna make love with you.
这是我和雅吉瓦印第安人的比赛
他是去年的区冠军.
And this is me with last year's
regional champion from Yakima.
他很可爱, 但有点慢. 下一张.
He was cute, but a little slow. Next.
噢, 这是我和
波咯·法明顿,
Oh, and this is me
with Brock Farmington,
来自斯波坎市的三A冠军.
triple-A champion from Spokane.
上身很有力,
Superior upper-body strength,
而四头肌就像桥桩.
and quads like bridge supports.
我用一分零5秒就把他钉到在地了.
l pinned him in a minute five.
下一张.
Next.
噢, 这是我
和我赢得的全部家当.
Oh, this is me
with all the stuff l won.
- 真好.
- 恭喜你成功了!.
- That's nice.
- Way to go.
谢谢你, 纳丁.
Thank you, Nadine.
好了, 现在,
Well, now,
我猜你们大家都想知道
为什么我们今天聚集在这里.
l suppose all of you are wondering
just why we've gathered here today.
看得出, 我所学到的是，
当一对夫妇打算离--
See, l learned that when a couple
is contemplating div--
分手,
Breaking up,
那, 有时当有其他人在场
的情况下，我们会
well, sometimes it's easier
to talk about our feelings
更容易讲出我们的感受.
when we're around other people.
那么, 纳丁,
要不，你先开始吧.
So, Nadine,
maybe you'd like to begin.
行.
Okay.
那, 我猜这一切都得
Well, l guess it all started
由我在学校大堂注意到
迈克的小屁屁开始讲起.
when l noticed Mike's buns
in the hall at school.
是的.
Yes.
那好, 你现在的感觉怎样?
Well, how are you feeling now?
嗯, 有一点内疚, 我想.
Well, a little guilty, l guess.
我意思是, 迈克和我正热乎着呢.
l mean, Mike and l are hot.
而且双峰小姐今晚就要举行了,
And Miss Twin Peaks is tonight,
还有就是品寇先生觉得
我很有演艺天赋.
and Mr. Pinkle thinks
l'm a show-business natural.
嗯, 我是说, 因为我太高兴了,
Well, l mean, because l'm so happy,
我担心艾德却因此而伤心.
l worry about Ed being sad.
艾德, 你有什么想
告诉纳丁吗?
Ed, is there something
that you'd like to tell Nadine?
纳丁...
Nadine...
...诺玛和我
正计划结婚.
...Norma and l
plan on getting married.
真的?
Really?
那, 那真是太好了, 小艾艾,
Well, that's wonderful, Eddie,
因为迈克和我
也正打算结婚呢.
because Mike and me
are getting married too.
那条是去城堡的路?
Which way is the castle?
- 我等着你呢.
- 谢谢, 哈里.
- l waited for you.
- Thanks, Harry.
他不大说话.
Not that he's too talkative.
他身体上没什么大碍.
医生抽血化验过了.
He checks out okay physically.
Doc ran some blood tests.
他被注射了大量的强力安定剂.
He's been shot full of haloperidol.
对.
Right.
加兰?
Garland?
是云顿·厄尔对你做的吗?
Did Windom Earle do this to you?
加兰?
Garland?
怪名字.
Odd name.
朱迪·加兰?
Judy Garland?
那是云顿·厄尔吗?
Was it Windom Earle?
我猜，是上帝干的.
lt was God, l suppose.
加兰, 他把你带去哪里了?
Garland, where did he take you?
是树林吗?
The woods?
你能讲得具体点?
Can you be more specific?
他们可爱.
They were lovely.
黑暗. 罗马尼亚国王
不能出席了.
Dark. The king of Romania
was unable to attend.
哈里, 这需要点时间.
Harry, this is gonna take some time.
- 我们还有多少时间?
- 不大够了.
- How much time we got?
- Not enough.
让他和我们留在一起.
或许会冒出些东西.
Let's leave him here with us.
Maybe something will bubble up.
哈里, 我们这次麻烦大了.
Harry, we're in trouble.
如果守夜门的入口
真的存在,
lf the door to the Black Lodge
does exist,
它可能会出现在某一个时间点上.
it probably exists at a point in time.
现在, 有目标了, 比如门,
Now, an object, such as a door,
通常出现在
某一个时空点.
normally exists at a point
in time and space.
相比之下,
By way of contrast,
一颗流星通常会存在于
一个时间点
a shooting star normally exists
at a point in time
飞越穿过一个空间连续.
over a continuum of space.
但从流星的角度去看,
就是完全不同的体验.
But taken from the star's point of view,
it's a completely different experience.
等等，你可把我搞糊涂了.
You just lost me.
如果我们不在正确的地方
正确的时间,
lf we're not at the right place
at exactly the right time,
就找不到入口.
we won't find our way in.
警长?
Sheriff?
4H俱乐部
和这一切有关系吗?
Could the Four-H Club
have anything to do with all of this?
难说, 安迪.
Doubtful, Andy.
这肯定是最后一个盒子了.
看它.
This has to be the last box.
Look at it.
我再也受不了这东西.
l can't take any more of this.
盒中盒.
Boxes inside boxes.
里面最好是
有价值的财富.
Whatever is in that
better be worth a fortune.
可能它根本就不是一个盒子.
Maybe it's not a box at all.
也许它只是
一块不锈钢.
Maybe it's just a block
of stainless steel.
- 埃卡最后的小恶作剧.
- 那可真是块好钢.
- Eckhardt's last little joke.
- lt'd be a good one.
让我们召集些
高智商的人来干这事.
Let's channel
some of that high wit into the job.
再来.
Again.
我真不能相信像这样一块小面包屑
l can't believe a little crumb like that
竟然经得起
千斤顶的虎头钳.
can stand up to
this Cram Jack all-duty vise.
数3下. 1, 2，3!
On three. One, two and three!
对不起, 安德鲁.
都是我不好.
l'm sorry, Andrew.
That was my fault.
蠢盒!
Dumb boxes!
安德鲁!
Andrew!
死盒.
Darn boxes.
射得好, 安德鲁.
Nice shooting, Andrew.
看.
Look at that.
一条钥匙!
A key!
哪里有钥匙,
哪里就有锁.
And where there's a key,
there's a lock.
把它保管好.
lt should be kept safe.
是的, 要一览无余.
Yes, in plain sight.
你们俩也互不信任?
You two don't trust each other?
我们当然信任.
Of course we do.
有其兄, 必有其妹.
Like brother, like sister.
这里怎样?
How about here?
放在蛋糕盘里.
ln the cake saver.
一览无余.
ln plain sight.
- 那么，我们有一条钥匙了.
- 是的, 我们有.
- So we have a key.
- Yes, we do.
你看起来真美.
You look truly beautiful.
给我们读一下你的演讲吧.
Read us your speech.
我宁愿现在讲一下
真相.
l'd rather talk about the truth
right now.
什么真相?
What truth is that?
我知道你和本杰明·荷恩
之间是发生过点事,
l know something's going on
with you and Benjamin Horne,
我想知道那是什么.
and l wanna know what it is.
唐娜,
别对你妈妈这样说话.
Donna,
don't talk to your mother like that.
你知道吗, 我真的很厌倦
你们还把我当小孩来说事.
You know, l'm really tired of you
talking to me like l'm a child.
我要知道这到底是怎么回事.
l wanna know what's going on.
唐娜, 我理解你的感受.
Donna, l understand your feeling.
但有些事情
你必须要相信.
But there are some things
you just have to trust.
你还年轻
还不知道所有事情的底线.
You're young
and you don't know all the limitations.
但我知道谎言的底线.
l know the limitations of lying.
我知道你要求我
要说实话.
l know that you raised me
to tell the truth.
我也对你有同样的期待.
l expect the same from you.
如果你不打算告诉我
需要知道的事,
lf you're not gonna tell me
what l need to know,
我会从本杰明·荷恩那里找出真相的.
l'll find out from Benjamin Horne.
- 别.
- 那就告诉我.
- No.
- Then tell me.
那好吧, 这是你的选择,
不是我的.
All right, this is your choice,
not mine.
唐娜.
Donna.
唐娜!
Donna!
苍天有眼.
By heavens.
安迪, 快来看看这个.
Andy, take a look at this.
你看错
4H俱乐部的,
What you mistook
for the Four-H Club,
4和H,
其实都是占星符号.
the four and the H,
are actually astrological symbols.
- 你意思是, 像行星?
- 为什么, 是的, 安迪.
- You mean, like planets?
- Why, yes, Andy.
它们代表着木星和土星.
They stand for Jupiter and Saturn.
其它符号
也是代表着行星,
Some of the others
represent planets as well,
就是这幅谜画的特别部分
涉及到行星运行轨道的确切位置.
but this particular part of the puzzle
pertains to a precise planetary position.
- 木星和土星要相连了.
- 那到底是什么意思?
- Jupiter and Saturn in conjunction.
- What's that supposed to mean?
是这样的, 哈里，在历史上,
每当木星和土星相连接时,
Well, historically, Harry,
when Jupiter and Saturn are conjunct,
能量和命运都会出现
巨大的转变.
there are enormous shifts
in power and fortune.
木星会因其影响
而膨胀,
Jupiter being expansive
in its influence,
土星, 则收缩.
Saturn, contractive.
两星相连促成了一种
强化, 集中的状态.
Conjunction suggests a state
of intensification, concentration.
这向我显示了
潜能会因此而出现爆炸性变化,
What this indicates to me
is the potential for explosive change,
- 善与恶.
- 那么，下一次相连是几时?
- good and bad.
- So when's the next conjunction?
这个, 现在, 让我们看看.
Well, now, let's see.
根据星历表...
According to the ephemeris...
...下一次相连预计
应该是1月至6月.
...the next conjunction is due
January to June.
我的上帝, 哈里.
My God, Harry.
守夜门的入口.
The door to the Lodge.
就会在那时开启.
就是这幅谜画要告诉我们的.
That's when it's open.
That's what the puzzle is telling us.
它在告诉我们
入口打开的时间.
lt's telling us
when it's gonna be open.
保护皇后.
Protect the queen.
如果它告诉我们时间,
那么它也一定告诉我们地点.
lf it's telling us when,
then it must also tell us where.
恐惧和爱开启大门.
Fear and love open the doors.
他刚刚说什么?
What's he saying?
他说,
"恐惧和爱开启大门."
He said,
''Fear and love open the doors.''
两扇门, 两个地方.
Two doors, two lodges.
恐惧开启黑色那一个.
Fear opens one, the black.
- 爱, 开启另一个.
- 那是什么意思?
- Love, the other.
- What's that mean?
我也不太清楚.
它就出现在我脑海里.
l don't know exactly.
lt just came to me.
皇后怎么--?
How does the queen--?
- 对啦, 皇后.
- 罗马尼亚的?
- Of course, the queen.
- Of Romania?
不是. 象棋比赛里的最后一只.
哈里, 跟着我的思路走.
No. The chess game's final piece.
Harry, follow my logic.
- 如果云顿·厄尔吃掉皇后--
- 但比赛还是没完，直到他把国王吃掉.
- lf Windom Earle takes the queen--
- Game's not over till he takes the king.
视情况而定. 或许当它开启时，
他要把皇后带到门外守候着.
That depends. Maybe he takes her
to the doorway when it opens.
- 我们讲的是哪一个皇后啊?
- 库珀探员.
- Which queen are we talking about?
- Agent Cooper.
等一下, 安迪.
Just a minute, Andy.
皇后. 皇后.
皇冠. 皇后.
The queen. The queen.
The crown. The queen.
- 哈里, 皇后.
- 库珀探员?
- Harry, the queen.
- Agent Cooper?
安迪, 别吵.
Andy, please.
哈里, 是双峰小姐.
Harry, Miss Twin Peaks.
- 圣烟啊, 那就是了.
- 对. 对.
- Holy smokes, that's it.
- Yeah. Yeah.
库珀探员, 等会儿.
Agent Cooper, please.
安迪.
Andy.
库, 原来盆栽装了窃听器.
Coop, the plant's been bugged.
这盆栽不是乔西送的, 哈里.
This bonsai isn't from Josie, Harry.
这盆栽是云顿·厄尔送来的.
This bonsai's from Windom Earle.
他比我们抢先了,
He's way ahead of us,
我们从一开始就在
为他工作.
and we've been working for him
from the beginning.
- 选美比赛几点开始?
- 马上就要开始了.
- What time does that contest start?
- Any minute.
我们出发.
Let's go.
库珀探员. 库珀探员!
Agent Cooper. Agent Cooper!
欢迎, 女士们，先生们.
Welcome, ladies and gentlemen.
我希望你们都有一个愉快的周末.
l hope you've had a good weekend.
欢迎各位
来参加双峰小姐选美大赛,
And welcome
to the Miss Twin Peaks Pageant,
这些可爱年轻
又有才的公民们中
in which one of these lovely
and talented young citizens
有一位很快就会被加冕为
双峰小姐呢.
will soon be crowned
Miss Twin Peaks.
那么, 我们的才艺展示环节
现在正式开始,
And now, commencing
our talent section of the show,
露西·莫兰.
Lucy Moran.
走吧.
Come on.
小镇, 伙计.
Small town, man.
怎么了,
你把全家人都带来了?
So, what,
did you bring your whole family?
我们已经动员了大量
警力进驻全场了.
We're pulling in deputies from all over
to surround the place.
他们随时会到.
They should be here any time.
哈里, 重要的是不管谁在比赛中胜出
都要接受24小时监护,
Harry, it is essential whoever wins
this contest receive 24-hour guard,
还有住宅保安, 我希望这奏效.
house security, l want the works.
等结果一宣布就执行.
As soon as she's announced.
我们的下一位参赛者是
拉娜·巴丁·妙福,
Our next entry
is Lana Budding-Milford,
她将为大家表演的舞蹈是...
who will perform a dance of...
...神秘异国软体爵士舞.
...contortionistic jazz exotica.
- 拉娜?
- 库珀探员--
- Lana?
- Agent Coop--
看那儿, 我的朋友, 这可是一个真正的艺术家啊.
There, my friend, is a real artist.
拯救我们森林的方法只有一个,
就是拒绝袖手旁观，拒绝看着它死去.
There is only one way to save a forest,
an idea, or anything of value.
这不但是一种概念
而且是对一切事物的价值观.
And that is by refusing to stand by
and watch it die.
自然法则,
对生命的重要意义
There is a law of nature,
which is more fundamental to life
远超过了人类所制定的法律.
than the laws of man.
当你所锺爱的事物
陷入危机时,
And when something you care about
is in danger,
你必须为拯救它而战
you must fight to save it
要不就会永远的失去它.
or lose it forever.
谢谢你们.
Thank you.
谢谢你, 欧蕊·荷恩.
Thank you, Audrey Horne.
现在，为大家穿插一段音乐短剧.
Now a brief musical interlude.
谢谢, 爸爸.
Thanks, Daddy.
我要出去那儿了.
l'm gonna go out there.
我要知道你和我妈妈
到底是怎么回事.
l wanna know what's going on
with you and my mother.
唐娜.
Donna.
我想最明智的做法就是,
l think the wisest course would be,
首先, 大家要聚在一起
然后再去谈论这事儿.
first of all, just to get together
and talk about this.
我可不这么认为.
l don't think so.
唐娜, 我觉得现在
真的不宜在这儿说事.
Donna, l really don't think
this is the time or the place.
你怎么解释那些老照片,
在阁楼里荷恩企业的无记名债券,
Old pictures,
Horne bearer bonds in the attic,
还有那些写给我妈妈的情信.
love letters to my mom.
我想说真相.
我想做正事.
l want to tell the truth.
l want to do the right thing.
还有一张没有父亲名字
在上面的出生证.
A birth certificate
with no father's name on it.
这到底是搞什么鬼,
荷恩先生?
What the hell's going on here,
Mr. Horne?
为什么没有任何人告诉我真相?
Why won't anyone tell me the truth?
唐娜.
Donna.
你妈妈和我...
Your mother and l...
你是我的父亲?
You're my father?
唐娜.
Donna.
为了阐明我的观点,
And to illustrate my point,
我想引用苏瓜密西族
西雅图酋长,
l'd like to quote these words
from Chief Seattle,
的一句名言:
leader of the Suquamish tribe:
"你们的死瞬即被遗忘
并一去不复返.
''Your dead are soon forgotten
and never return.
这曾给予他们生命的美丽世界
却永不会遗忘我们的死亡.
Our dead never forget the beautiful
world that gave them being.
它们仍热爱它青翠的山谷,
They still love its verdant valleys,
潺潺低语的川流,
雄伟庄严的山峦.
its murmuring rivers,
its majestic mountains.
当最后一个红种人
在地球上消失时,
When the last red man has vanished
from this earth,
这些森林和海岸
仍将怀抱着他们的灵魂."
these forests and shores
will still hold their spirits.''
因此，印第安人对地球的爱
For the lndians love the earth
犹如一个新生儿的爱
它是母亲的心跳.
as a newborn loves
its mother's heartbeat.
为什么我们都失去了
如此良辰美景?
Why have we all lost touch
with this beauty?
也许拯救森林，要从拯救
我们内心仅存那点良知开始
Maybe saving a forest starts
with preserving some of the feelings
每天，它都正在一点一点死去.
that die inside us every day.
而我们却极力否认
那部分属于自己.
Those parts of ourselves
that we deny.
但是，如果我们
不尊重内陆,
For if we cannot respect
that interior land,
也就是不尊重
我们所走的这片土地.
then neither can we respect
the land we walk.
因此，让我们, 在地球上
轻柔的来去,
So let us, in walking gently
upon the earth,
造福后代.
leave behind a simple legacy.
我们是新时代的斗士,
That we're new warriors,
是爱地球并努力拯救它的
mystic warriors who love the earth
神秘斗士.
and tried to save it.
非常感谢你们.
Thank you very much.
感谢我们所有的参赛者.
Thanks to all our contestants.
投票现在开始,
然后我们将宣布我们的冠军.
Balloting will now commence,
and we will then announce our winner.
你们俩都已经忘了
今天是什么日子吗?
Have you both forgotten
what day this is?
双峰小姐日?
Miss Twin Peaks Day?
今天是我那尚未出世的孩子
迎接父亲的大日子.
Today is the day
my unborn child receives a dad.
这正是我要说的.
lt was right on the tip of my tongue.
我已经决定了
l have decided
不管是从个体生物责任感
去考虑，还是别的,
that regardless of which individual
is biologically responsible,
我还是想让安迪做
我孩子的父亲.
that l want Andy to be the father
of my child.
真的?
Really?
对不起, 基巴, 但我必须做最好的，
为了...他叫什么名字好呢?
l'm sorry, Dick, but l just have to do
what's best for little what's-his-name.
噢, 不, 没关系. 一个合理的选择.
Oh, no, not at all. A sound choice.
衷心地祝贺你,
我最亲爱的安德鲁.
Heartiest congratulations,
dearest Andrew.
那么, 如果你们俩不介意,
我真的要走了，都等着我投票呢.
Now, if you'll both excuse me,
l do have a vote to cast myself.
这是祝小孩的.
Here's to the children.
别用那么沮丧的声调嘛.
Don't sound so disappointed.
我的上帝, 露西.
My God, Lucy.
你做了这个决定
我太荣幸了.
l'm so honored
you made this decision.
我保证我会做一个好父亲的.
And l promise l'll be a great father.
但现在
But right now
我得去找库珀探员.
l've got to find Agent Cooper.
男人.
Men.
宣布结果的
时刻到了.
lt is time
to make the announcement.
我们新一届双峰小姐大赛
The winner of the contest
的冠军是...
and our new Miss Twin Peaks is...
...安妮·伯本.
...Annie Blackburn.
女士们，先生们,
你们的新晋双峰小姐来了!
Ladies and gentlemen,
your new Miss Twin Peaks!
这简直就是一种侮辱.
This is an outrage.
她在这镇上住了
还不到15分钟.
She's been living in this town
about 1 5 minutes.
你搞什么鬼，脑袋进水了?
And what the hell got into you?
她做了一个精彩的演讲.
She gave a beautiful speech.
她言词中带有与生俱来的力量
lnherent in her message were words
即便是我们中最懦弱的人
都无不受到感染.
even the most craven of us
can ill afford to ignore.
这是怎么回事?
What's happening?
各位, 请,
请保持冷静.
Everybody, please,
please stay calm.
老天爷.
Good Lord.
这边.
This way.
冷静. 各位冷静.
别惊慌! 这边来.
Settle down. Everybody settle down.
Don't panic! This way.
我会帮助你的.
l will help you.
安妮?
Annie?
- 哈里.
- 什么?
- Harry.
- What?
- 他掳走了安妮.
- 什么?
- He took Annie.
- What?
他抓了安妮.
He got Annie.
混帐东西. 他离这儿不会
超过半英里的. 我们会逮到他的.
Bastard. He won't get half a mile
from here. We'll get him.
库珀探员,
我一直到处找你呢.
Agent Cooper,
l've been looking all over for you.
安迪, 他们外面肯定
需要你.
Andy, they're gonna need you
outside.
这很重要.
This is important.
对办公室里的那幅洞穴画,
我终于想通了.
That cave painting in the office,
l finally figured it out.
- 什么?
- 我记得之前在某处见过它.
- What?
- l knew l'd seen it someplace before.
我还知道它告诉我们要去哪里.
l know where it's telling us to go.
它根本不是一幅谜画.
lt's not a puzzle at all.
而是一幅地图.
lt's a map.